<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Visualisation on Jennifer Snape | Data Science</title>
    <link>/categories/visualisation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Visualisation on Jennifer Snape | Data Science</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/visualisation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with R Shiny</title>
      <link>/2018/04/getting-started-with-r-shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/04/getting-started-with-r-shiny/</guid>
      <description>Interactive Visualisations in R  This post was inspired by this competition, hosted by JumpingRivers. The competition asks you to extract data from their GitHub account containing the details of R groups and R ladies groups around the world. With this data it asks you to create a visualisation, of any kind. I’ve been working on my visualisation skills in R so I thought I would have a go at entering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How many Munros have I climbed?</title>
      <link>/2018/03/how-many-munros-have-i-climbed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/03/how-many-munros-have-i-climbed/</guid>
      <description>Mapping the Munros in R using ggmap   After learning to plot graphs in R using ggplot2, the next visualisation technique in R I wanted to learn was how to plot geographical data on maps. There is a package called ggmap that works with ggplot2 to allow you to plot maps. You download a map of your chosen location from google maps and use it as a layer in the ggplot2 plotting system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who has won the most Brit Awards?</title>
      <link>/2018/02/who-has-won-the-most-brit-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/02/who-has-won-the-most-brit-awards/</guid>
      <description>Visualising the Brit Awards using ggplot2   When I first learn R at university, we were taught to do all our graphs using the base R graph functions. I had no idea until earlier this year that there was another way! While searching for R help on different forums, I kept running into a plotting package called ‘ggplot2’ that everyone seemed to be using. I decided I needed to do my research and find out what all the hype is about.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>